<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Explore Kenya</string>
    <string name="appname">Explore Kenya</string>
    
    
    <!-- maps key-->
    <string name="google_maps_api_key">0A8EMCJX_pL4K1YzpKcm4Es4vP49jV3uAnvLOLA</string>
                     <!-- Default key  0SEQj06BtcE9oaRzUZikV9v6fXVcdJIaaF9c8ug-->
    
    <!-- Description UI-->
     <string name="description_home">ExploreKenya</string>
     <string name="description_cities">Locations</string>
     <string name="description_parks">Parks</string>
     <string name="description_culture">Culture</string>
     <string name="description_events">Events</string>
     <string name="description_info">Info</string>
     <string name="description_logo">Home</string>
     <string name="description_search">Search</string>
     <string name="description_share">Share</string>
     
     <!-- Description Manifest-->
     <string name="comment">Comment</string>
     <string name="comments">Comments</string>
     <string name="location_nairobi">Nairobi City</string>
     <string name="location_mombasa">Mombasa City</string>
     <string name="location_malindi">Malindi</string>
     <string name="location_kisumu">Kisumu City</string>
     <string name="location_nakuru">Nakuru</string>
     <string name="location_nanyuki">Nanyuki</string>
     <string name="description_food">Kenyan Cuisine</string>
     <string name="description_sports">Kenyan Sports</string>
     <string name="description_lifestyle">Kenyan Lifestyle</string>
     <string name="description_history">History of Kenya</string>
    
    <!-- Network Error on Loading  -->
      <string name="notification_msg">No Internet Connection.</string>
      <string name="notification_msg_search">No Search results obtained.</string>
     <string name="notification_prompt">Explore Kenya.</string>
     <string name="exit_btn">Exit</string>
     <string name="ok_btn">OK</string>
      <string name="empty_field">Search field  Cannot be Blank</string>
   
     
     <!-- Maping stuff -->
     <string name="enable_gps_network">Enable GPS Settings.</string>
      <string name="enable_message">Please confirm GPS  settings to resolve current location</string>
      <string name="settings_btn">Settings</string>
      <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
     
    <!-- Comment -->
    <string name="empty_name">Please provide your Name.</string>
    <string name="empty_comment">Please submit a comment.</string>
    
    <!-- TabLayout UI -->
    <string name="tab_cities">Locations</string>
    <string name="tab_tourism">Tourism</string>
    <string name="tab_culture">Culture</string>
    <string name="tab_events">Events</string>
    <string name="tab_info">Info</string>
    
    <!-- Settings UI-->
    <string name="chk_auto_fetch">Notification</string>
    <string name="hint_auto_fetch">Periodic Event Notification</string>
    <string name="vibrate">Vibrate Alert</string>
    <string name="hint_vibrate">Will cause phone to vibrate</string>
    <string name="flash_led">Flashing LED</string>
	<string name="hint_flash_led">Cause phone\'s LED to flash</string>
	<string name="setting_title">Explore Kenya Settings.</string>
	
	<!-- Locations -->
	<string name="more">:More</string>
    <string name="attractions">Attractions</string>
    <string name="map">Locations Map</string>
    
    <string name="crash_toast_text">Internet Connection Lost</string>

    
    <!-- Content I should really have this on the server -->
	<string name="nairobi">Nairobi is the capital of Kenya and largest city of Kenya. 
The name Nairobi  comes from the Maasai phrase Enkare Nairobi, which translates 
to cold water, the Maasai name of the Nairobi river, which in turn lent its name to the city. 
However,it is popularly known as the "Green City in the Sun" and is surrounded by several expanding 
villa suburbs. Residents of Nairobi are known as Nairobians\n</string>
<string name="nairobi1">
The city is located at 1°17′S 36°49′E and occupies 696 square kilometres (270 sq mi).
Nairobi is situated between the cities of Kampala and Mombasa.
The Ngong Hills, located to the west of the city, are the most prominent geographical 
feature of the Nairobi area. Mount Kenya is situated north of Nairobi and Mount Kilimanjaro is
towards the south-east. Both mountains are visible from Nairobi on a clear day.
The Nairobi River and its tributaries traverse through the Nairobi County. 
The late Nobel Peace Prize laureate Wangari Maathai has fought fiercely to save the indigenous 
Karura Forest in northern Nairobi which was under threat of being replaced by 
housing and other infrastructure.</string>

<string name="mombasa">Mombasa is the second-largest city in Kenya. 
Lying next to the Indian Ocean, it has a major port and an international airport. 
The city also serves as the centre of the coastal tourism industry.
The city has a population of 939,370, as per the 2009 census,
and is located on Mombasa Island, which is separated 
from the mainland by two creeks: Tudor Creek and Kilindini Harbour. 
The island is connected to the mainland to the north by the Nyali Bridge, 
to the south by the Likoni Ferry and to the west by the Makupa Causeway, 
alongside which runs the Kenya-Uganda Railway. The port serves both Kenya 
and countries of the interior, linking them to the Ocean. 
The city is served by Moi International Airport located in
the northwest mainland suburb of Chaani, northwest of Changamwe area.\n</string>
 <string name="mombasa2">The Nothern Shoreline of Mombasa is renowned for its vibrant 24-hour
 entertainment offers, including both family entertainment 
(water parks, cinemas, bowling, etc.), sports (watersports, 
mountain biking and gokarting), culinary offers (restaurants offering a 
wide range of specialties 
from Kenya, China, Japan, India, Italy, Germany and other countries) 
and night life(bars, pubs, clubs, discothèques, etc.).
Moi International Airport serves the city of Mombasa. 
It is located in Port Reitz area, also known locally as Chaani 
area on the mainland metropolitan area. 
Flights to Nairobi and other Kenyan, European 
and Middle Eastern destinations depart from the 
airport. Besides Mombasa and Nairobi are 
well connected by chartered flights operated via Wilson airport. </string>
<string name="malindi">Malindi is a town on Malindi Bay at the mouth of the Galana River, 
lying on the Indian Ocean coast of Kenya. 
It is 120 kilometres northeast of Mombasa. 
It is the capital of the Malindi District.
Tourism is the major industry in Malindi. 
The city is exceptionally popular among Italian tourists. 
Malindi is served with a domestic airport and a highway between Mombasa and Lamu.
 The nearby Watamu resort and Gedi Ruins (also known as Gede) are 
south of Malindi. The mouth of the Sabaki River lies in northern Malindi. 
The Watamu and Malindi Marine National Parks form a continuous protected 
coastal area south of Malindi. The area shows classic examples of Swahili 
architecture.
Malindi is home to the Malindi Airport and Broglio Space Centre.\n </string>
<string name="malindi1">Malindi has been a Swahili settlement since the 14th century. 
Once rivaled only by Mombasa for dominance in this part of East Africa, Malindi has traditionally been a 
port city for foreign powers. In 1414, the town was visited by the fleet of the Chinese explorer Zheng He.
 Malindi\'s ruler sent a personal envoy with a giraffe as a present to China on that fleet.
The Portuguese explorer Vasco da Gama met Malindi authorities in 1498 to sign a trade agreement and 
hire a guide for the voyage to India, when he erected a coral pillar. The pillar stands to this day.
It is a fairly popular tourist attraction for both local and international tourists.
 In 1499 the Portuguese established a trading post in Malindi that served as a resting stop
on the way to and from India. A church dates from this era.
Many traditional buildings survive, including the Juma Mosque 
and palace on the beach, a stretch popular with tourists.\n</string>
<string name="kisumu">Kisumu is a port city in western Kenya at 1,131 m (3,711 ft).
 It is the third largest 
city in Kenya, the principal city of western Kenya, 
the immediate former capital of Nyanza Province and the headquarters 
of Kisumu County.
It is the largest city in Nyanza region and second most important 
city after Kampala in the greater Lake Victoria basin.
The port was founded in 1901 as the main inland terminal 
of the Uganda Railway and named Port Florence. 
Although trade stagnated in the 1980s and 1990s, 
it is again growing around oil exports.
Kisumu literally means a place of barter 
trade "sumo". The city has "Friendship" status with Cheltenham, 
UK and "sister city" status with Roanoke, 
Virginia and Boulder, Colorado, USA.\n</string>
<string name="kisumu1">Attractions in the city include Kibuye Market, the Kisumu Museum, an 
impala sanctuary, a bird sanctuary, 
Hippo Point, and the nearby Kit Mikaye and Ndere Island National Park.
Before the jet airline era, Kisumu was a landing point on the British flying boat passenger 
and mail route from Southampton to Cape Town. Kisumu linked Port Bell and Nairobi.
Kisumu is served by Kisumu Airport, with regular daily flights to Nairobi and elsewhere. 
Plans to expand the airport in anticipation of increased trade brought about by the recreated
 East African Community of Kenya, Tanzania and Uganda are already in high gear with works 
expected to be complete soon.
Lake Victoria ferries have operated from the port 
linking the railway to Mwanza and Bukoba in Tanzania, and to Entebbe, 
Port Bell, and Jinja in Uganda.\n</string>
<string name="nakuru">Nakuru, the provincial capital of Kenya\'s Rift Valley province, 
with roughly 300,000 inhabitants, and currently the fourth largest
urban centre in the country, 
lies about 1850 m above sea level.
Nakuru is home to Lake Nakuru, one of the Rift Valley soda lakes, 
which forms part of the Lake Nakuru National Park. 
The park has large numbers of flamingoes that can be seen 
foraging in the shallow lake. The park also has many wild 
animals that can be seen during a safari. 
Apart from the animals numerous other sites of interest are accessible from 
Nakuru. These include Menengai Crater, a dormant volcano. 
Small fumaroles and steam vents can regularly be observed within the forested 
caldera from above. The second largest surviving volcanic crater in the world, 
it plunges 483 m down from the rim and the summit is accessible by foot or
vehicle 8 km from the main road to Nyahururu. 
The wood-covered crater ground is a nature reserve.\n</string>
<string name="nakuru1" >Although Lake Bogoria and Lake Baringo are in Baringo District, they are easily accessible from Nakuru.
These are major tourist attraction sites too.
The Rift Valley Sports Club lies in the centre of the town. 
A number of sporting activities are hosted at this club and popular among them is cricket. 
The local Indian community can be found at cricket fixtures throughout the year. 
The town hosts an annual rugby festival dubbed "The Great Rift 10-a-side" which features teams from across the East Africa region.
Hyrax Hill Prehistoric Site, discovered by the Leakeys in 1926, is considered a major Neolithic and Iron Age site. 
The adjoining museum features finds from various nearby excavations.\n</string>
<string name="nanyuki" >Nanyuki is  town in central-east Rift Valley region of Kenya lying 
northwest of Mount Kenya along the A2 road and at the terminus of the branch 
railway from Nairobi. It is situated just north of the Equator (0° 01\' North). 
It was founded in 1907 by British settlers, some of whose descendants still live 
in and around the town. Nanyuki is currently the main airbase of the Kenya Air Force. 
The British Army also keeps a base at The Nanyuki Show Ground (NSG) from where it 
conducts yearly desert and jungle training exercises on the mountain and in the arid 
areas to the north. Nanyuki is the capital of Laikipia County. 
In addition to a town hall, therefore, it also houses the county headquarters.\n</string>
<string name="nanyuki1" >Climbers and backpackers visit Nanyuki on their way to or from Mount Kenya along
 the Sirimon and Burguret routes and many other tourists pass through the town. 
Nanyuki therefore has many hotels, of which Mount Kenya Safari Club and Sportsman\’s 
Arms Hotel are the most prominent and best known. Other hotels include Lion’s Court, 
Equatorial Hotel, Mount Kenya Paradise Hotel and Joskaki Hotel. 
The oldest restaurant in town is The Marina and it is still fairly popular. 
Several years ago, a restaurant was opened south of Nanyuki built inside a huge tree. 
Named “Trout Tree Restaurant” its main attraction is obviously trout prepared in various ways. 
Patrons can also visit the trout breeding installation at the foot of the tree. 
Another notable restaurant is "Barneys" located at Nanyuki Civil Airfield, 
once the base of the No. 1340 Flight RAF, which flew Harvards during the Mau Mau Uprising.\n
A park lies in the centre of the town and two rivers, the Nanyuki and Liki Rivers, pass through it.
The Equator passes through the southern part of Nanyuki. 
One crosses it when approaching Nanyuki on the A2 from the south. 
This spot is popular with tourists who have themselves photographed there. 
Some people are usually at hand to show them the  effect of the Coriolis force, 
which they say makes draining water swirl clockwise or anticlockwise depending on whether 
one is on the northern or southern hemisphere.\n
Nanyuki can be reached by air. Its airport lies 6.5 km (4 mi) south of the town and is served by 
light aircraft along the highway to Nairobi . 
There is a regular air service by Air Kenya, which is very convenient 
for businessmen and tourists
.The town is also reachable using the Tarmac road from Nairobi or The Railway. 
Tourists can visit a number of parks and reserves in the vicinity of Nanyuki, 
the most obvious one being Mount Kenya National Park. Others are Sweetwaters Game Reserve,
 Lewa Wildlife Conservancy, Samburu National Reserve and Shaba National Reserve.
Art exhibitions, plays and musicals are regularly held at the Lily Pond Arts Centre
Nanyuki has some of the cleanest water in Kenya since the water supply source is a 
river on Mt. Kenya.\n</string>
<string name="history" > Detailed History of Kenya.</string>

<string name="history1" >
Ancient Kenya History dictates that early forms of man once roamed Kenya approximately 
4 million years ago. These ancient life forms were probably some of the same life forms that 
roamed Tanzania and other areas of East Africa.\n\n

Activity builds up in Kenya\n\n

At the wake of 2000 B.C, Cushitic people of Northern Africa moved into Kenya. 
Two millenniums later, around 200 A.D, the Bantu made an entry into Kenya and settled along 
Kenya\'s coast. They were later followed several hundred years later (10th-14th century) by 
the Nilotic people, who occupied the Great Rift Valley plains.\n\n

Did you know?\n\n

Despite the Cushites\’ early arrival into Kenya, they are still a minority group today.
Of the Arabs and the Portuguese
These two groups arguably contribute to some of the most defining moments of Kenyan history. 
It was a Game of Thrones, a battle for power, as these two groups were engaged in constant wrangles
over leadership and power in the coast.\n\n

Arabs\n\n

Came in earlier than the Portuguese (as early as 700 A.D)
Forged the Swahili culture and language. This was done through intermarriages with the Bantu 
along the coast.Portuguese\n\n

They came in at the outset of 1500 A.D and immediately took power from the Arabs.
Built the illustrious Fort Jesus in 1593.
The Portuguese were later stamped out of power by the Imam of Omam at the fall of the 1600s. 
This reinstated Islamic control over the coast.\n\n</string>
 <string name="history2" > Kenya Colonial History </string> 
 <string name="history3" >
The colonial history of Kenya starts with the Berlin Conference of 1885 when European nations divided Africa among themselves. 
In 1894 the British government declared the East African Protectorate over Kenya and Uganda and in 1920 the protectorate 
became a colony. The Kenya historical events timeline below highlights key events of the colonial period.\n\n

1944 Kenyan African Union (KAU) formed to campaign for independence.\n
1947 Jomo Kenyatta becomes KAU leader.\n 
1947 The Mau Mau rebel movement is born.\n
1952 Mau Mau activities intensify. The colonial government declares a state of emergency. Kenyatta, Achieng Aneko and others are arrested.\n
1953 Kenyatta is sentenced to seven years imprisonment on charges of leading the Mau Mau.\n 
1959 Kenyatta is released from prison.\n 
1960 The state of emergency ends. Britain begins preparing Kenya for majority African rule. 
James Gichuru Oginga Odinga and others form Kenya African National Union (KANU)\n
1963 June 1: Kenya achieves internal self-government (Madaraka).\n 
1963 December 12: Kenya gains independence. Jomo Kenyatta becomes Prime Minister.\n</string>
<string name="food" > One delightful element about Kenyan food is its diverse flavor. 
 Kenyan cooking draws upon a variety of ethnic traditions merged with the seasonings
 and tastes of outside countries. Because of Kenya\'s long-standing relationship with 
 foreign settlers and its colonization by the British, the taste, cooking methods and 
 presentation of Kenyan foods have been greatly influenced by the Indians, Arabs, Europeans,
 and Pakistanis as well as some western countries.\n\n
 Kenyan food is mainly traditional and nearly all of Kenya\'s tribes boast a specific meal as 
their very own staple food. Typical Kenyan cuisine is readily available in almost every Kenyan eatery; 
you can find it served in restaurants, hotels, clubs and entertainment venues with an African flair.\n
Ingredients in Kenyan Cuisine\n\n
The most popular foods in Kenya are fresh foods from the country\'s vast resources. Farmland, lakes 
and the Indian Ocean provide readily available vegetables, fruits and meats. Often, the ingredients 
used to prepare a Kenyan dish are fresh, very cheap and easily used to make a quick meal. Common vegetables 
include kale, spinach, cabbage, tomatoes, beans, potatoes, avocados and other leafy greens, while beef and 
goat meat are the common meats served in a Kenyan meal. Fish, chicken, and mutton are available but are more expensive.\n\n
Tropical fruits such as mangoes, oranges, pineapples, bananas, papaws, and pears are affordable, plentiful and 
popular on Kenyan tables, their availability dictated by the season. Other ingredients used in typical Kenyan
 dishes and recipes include rice, corn meal, and wheat and millet flour. Kenyans are avid tea drinkers, thus hot
 beverages such as Kenyan tea and coffee are often served with meals. Cold beverages like soda, juice, and domestic 
 and international beers are also available in restaurants, hotels, pubs and entertainment spots. \n\n
 What About Other Foods?\n\n
Adventurous meat eaters can also indulge in safe wildlife game meat, such as crocodile and ostrich, served in 
specialized restaurants. Game meat is rarely eaten in Kenyan homes. While most ingredients are used for ethnic 
food preparations, Western foods such as french fries, burgers, pizza, and pasta are readily available in some 
restaurants and fast-food places. \n </string> 

<string name="food1" >Common Ethnic Foods in Kenya\n </string>  
<string name="food2" > 
Ugali - a semi-hard cake made of maize (corn) flour or millet flour. It\'s a favorite meal for all Kenyans and 
usually accompanies fish, meat, Roast Meat(nyama choma), meat stews, sukuma wiki or other greens.\n</string>    
 <string name="food3" >Sukuma Wiki - a vegetable stew made of leafy green vegetables, mainly collards or kale. 
Sukuma wiki is the foundation of many Kenyan meals. The word sukuma wiki is Swahili for to stretch the week,
implying that sukuma wiki is a food used to stretch the meals to last for the entire week.\n</string>
 <string name="food4" >Nyama Choma - The most popular dish in Kenya is this roasted beef or goat meat meal. It is mainly cooked over an
open fire and served with ugali and kachumbari or mixed vegetables. </string>
 <string name="food5" >Kachumbari - a fine mixture of chopped tomatoes, onions, pepper, cilantro, lemon juice and in some cases, avocado. 
It is usually served with nyama choma and ugali. </string>
<string name="food6" >Chapati - a round, flat unleavened bread cooked on a griddle to a soft brown color and served with meat stew and
vegetables.</string>
<string name="food7" >Ingoho - chicken cooked -Luhya style- by the Luhya tribe of Western Kenya. It is their signature meal, which 
they serve to important visitors.</string>
<string name="food8" >Pilau - rice cooked as rice pilaf, flavored with Indian spices. Pilau is a common dish served during Kenyan 
parties, celebrations and festive seasons. </string>
<string name="food9" >Wali - rice boiled in coconut milk. Along the Kenyan coast, wali is a popular meal of the Swahili and Mijikenda
 tribes. Palm trees are grown all across Kenya\'s coastline and fresh coconut is always readily available.</string>
<string name="food10" >Karanga - a meat and potato stew, usually served with ugali or rice.</string>
<string name="food11" >Kienyeji / Irio - potatoes mashed with either beans/peas or maize and pumpkin leaves, then sautéed with onions
 and served with either beef stew or vegetables. An alternative is mashing boiled maize and beans to make irio.</string>
 <string name="food12" >Maandazi - deep fried pastries (similar to doughnuts) served for breakfast with tea or coffee.
 They also serve well as a snack for late afternoon tea/coffee.</string>
 <string name="food13" >Chai - tea boiled with milk and sugar. It\'s served hot and is the beverage of choice for most Kenyans.</string>
 <string name="food14" >Samosa - a delicious deep-fried, square-shaped, meat-filled dough that is served as a snack or appetizer.</string>
 <string name="food15" >Uji - porridge traditionally made from fermented millet, corn flour mix or a mixture of millet flour, 
maize meal and powdered milk. Because of its high nutritional value, uji is a popular drink prepared 
for infants, adolescents, nursing mothers and those who are sick.</string>
    
    
    

    


</resources>